identify high probability setups in 15
minutes or less take a trade whether
it's a buyer or sell you put your stop
loss for your take profit and then you
just have to forget you can literally go
to work at the gym maybe do whatever you
want all you have to do is occasionally
just check up on the trade to see if
it's hit your take profit and then two
days later boom your profits have been
made these are the swing trading
operation looks like or at least the way
that I do so what is Swing trading so
the Google definition of trading is a
trade that is held past one day or more
you know usually like a week right but
what stream trading really is is just
trading with the higher time frames
whether they are the weekly daily time
frames and you're just using this as
your take profit zones because you know
you're setting and forgetting you're
using the higher time frames to reach a
larger profit not saying you can't make
money with scallops or with the smaller
trades but you know it's a lot more
volatile and you're more prone to get
stopped out when you're trading with
swing trading or into day trading the
way that I do you're trading with the
higher time frames you're a lot better
winning and your chances of winning are
a lot higher because you're going with
the majority of the time frames your pro
Trend trading and I preached this all of
the time now how is this different from
other types of trading let's say
scalping day trading or even intraday
trading so basically what scalping is
you're just in and out within the hour
two three hours or also the session
you're basically in and out fast you
just want to get money in the day you
want to catch a quick move and then
you're out so this is actually what 99
of Traders try when they first come to
the markets because they see it as easy
quick money but this is where the
majority of Traders gets you know
smacked by the markets and they get to
stop losses and they just get hit by the
market very hard because they come in
too aggressive to stop them then next we
have day trading so day trading is also
a very common style of trading because
you're just in and out within the day so
you either have a trade in the morning
you get out by the night time or you get
in at night time you get out by the
morning which is a very common way of
trading and I've kind of been
implementing something like it very
recently with my strategy and is
extremely effective intraday is when
you're holding for a little bit longer
than a day trade so day trade and entry
day you're pretty much buying on like
four hour zones two hour zones one hour
zones and then you're maybe having daily
take profits but you know you're just in
and out with the day so you're just
using the four hour structure and the
daily structure mainly then next we have
swing trading which is like I'd say like
the best one a lot of all of them
because I have a mix of all the
different types of trading with my swing
trading strategy so basically using the
higher time frames to identify the trend
to them pretty much buy with the trend
and then you use daily timeframes to
kind of have like your little smaller
zones and then you use the lower time
frames like four hour two hour one hour
to get into the trade to then have the
longer take profits meaning that you
have the most precise entries because
you use the lower time frames and then
you have the largest take profits
because you're using the higher time
frame so this is some of the pros and
cons of Swing trading the big big big
Pros right off the bat is you make way
more money because you have larger take
profits since you're going with the
higher time from your less prone to
losing because you're pro-trend trading
so not only do you make more money but
you're more likely to make more money
and then since you're going with the
trend you're less likely to lose so
you're not losing as much when you're
swing trading along with the fact that
it is the most easiest and it is the
less stress so it requires minimal
amount of time with minimal amount of
effort whether you're entering trade or
whether you're just set up forgetting
letting it hit your take profit or your
stop-off the stop loss is going to get
it I'm not gonna lie but the cons really
is really only one con and that's that
it just requires patience a lot of
traders that want to come into the
market and they want to take 10 trades
the same day that's not how this works
like I've gone like a whole week without
taking a trade and it's beautiful
because I'm just standing on the
sidelines watching everybody's stop loss
get hit while I'm just waiting for a
nice trade setup to pop up so when
you're not involved in the markets it's
good because the swing trading gets you
out where you're not supposed to be in
and it gets you in right when you're
supposed to be in I see the only
kindness patience because you can
probably take one two maybe three trades
Maybe week but if each trade has a one
to three risk to reward to me that's
positive all day and it's stress-free so
this is a side note the most important
thing when swing trading is the trend is
your friend you want to go wherever the
majority of the Market's going so that
is one the second one being you need to
buy with a weekly or daily area of
interest that is it I don't care if the
four hour looks good I don't care if the
two hour that's good it does not matter
the four hour and two hour zones are not
going to be respected as strong or as
solid as the weekly or daily and that is
a simple fact I can put out the receipts
you take 10 trades buying at a daily
area of interest and 10 trades buying at
a four hour area of Interest your 10
trades on The Daily airventions are
going to win more than the four and
simple fact because the stones are much
stronger and much more respectful before
we go to the charts and I show you some
of my swing trades I've created a class
to where anyone can Master my most
profitable skill ever where it can make
you generate anywhere from four to six
thousand dollars every single month but
realistically only dedicating probably
an hour or two a day so watch it click
on this video right here make sure to
watch it after this class is over so
everything is sent so make sure to watch
this video once we're done with this one
all right so now I'm gonna walk you guys
through this trade where I made 85 000
in under 24 hours almost breaking my
record if I would have just set it
forget a little bit more but you know I
but it's okay I'm gonna walk you guys
through from the moment that I analyzed
it on Sunday swings to all the way where
I entered where I placed my stop loss
where I entered where I put my uh take
profit every day I'm gonna walk you guys
to the whole entire trade so make sure
you guys pay attention so the first
thing when we go to the market with we
we already know is we identify the trend
where is the trend going you guys
already know I said this earlier the
trend is your friend you want to go
wherever the majority of the markets are
going so if you notice here we have the
weekly time frame is air so as you can
tell this Market structure is headed to
the downtown lower low lower high lower
low and this is where we potentially
created a new lower high obviously if we
end up breaking under so right now we
can tell the weekly is there so yes I do
this for every single trade because if
you're not holding yourself accountable
to mark up your charts and follow your
trading plan then who is nobody's going
to be behind you while you're trading
like hey make sure to do that so this is
where all the Traders they fail and they
just end up losing because they don't
hold themselves accountable I literally
do this for every single trade so weekly
time frame is bearish then we go down to
the Daily time frame and as you can tell
the daily time frame went from being
bullish to being bearish so we were here
creating higher highs and higher lows so
then creating lower lows and lower highs
so at the time of us taking this very
trade right here we were bearish as you
guys can tell you have here daily time
frame Bears so this would be the lower
high and then this would be the lower
low because this is the higher high this
is the higher low we then broke the
structure so this time frame here is now
bearish so actually this would be at the
lower high and then this would be the
lower low so at the time of us taking
this trade this is exactly what it
looked like so after we identified that
the daily is bearish then we go down to
the four out so on the four hour we
would do the same exact thing and as you
guys can tell the four hour structure is
also the bearish because we were
creating higher highs and higher lows
and then we shifted to the downside to
making this time frame bearish so the
lower low would be here and then the
lower high would be here so as long as
you remains under these two lines then
we can do here whatever we want we are
embarrassed the moment we body close
above we go bullish the moment we body
close under then this turns into the new
lower low and then this turns in to the
lower high so this is where we would
then identify that the four hour is
bearish as well meaning we have three
time frames in sync all time frames are
going down why would you be interested
in buying on the one hour time frame or
38 minute time frame or 15 minute it is
a waste of time you only want to take a
trade with the majority of the markets
are going this is what I expressed every
single Sunday when I get on the call
with the students so as you can tell
here the weekly time frame is bearish
the daily time frame is bearish and then
the four hour time frame is bearish the
only thing that makes sense is to sell
so we're only looking to sell we're
going to only find an area of interest
to sell so now this is where I only look
for my areas of interest on The Daily or
the weekly area of Interest so as you
can tell I found this Zone on The Daily
because we need a minimum of three
touches to find area of Interest this is
where we have
area of interest uh Touch One
touch two and then touch three so we
have three touches on the air Adventures
making this a solid area of Interest
whenever we are above we're buying
whenever we are under we're selling
whenever we are under we're selling so
in this case not only are we under the
area of interest but all time frames are
heading down so it's like setting
yourself up for Success right now so
after we understand that the three time
frames are in sync my next Confluence is
we are selling
at a daily area of Interest again I can
only identify an area of interest if we
have a minimum of three touches so this
right here the way that I grade it is
that every time frame is a 10 towards
your grade uh in terms of trend so this
right here this is going to be 10
percent
this is going to be ten percent and then
this is going to be 10 so let's say for
example that the four hour would be
bullish so let's just suppose that this
is bullish
um like this then this would only make
this trade a 20 because we only have two
time frames in order to take the cell
let's say you want to take the buy for
whatever crazy reason then this would
only be a 10 towards your grade because
you only have the four hour bullish
again I only identify Trend in these
three time frames everything under here
is simply for entry signals so obviously
we're not looking to buy because that
makes no sense we want the majority time
frames in our favor so this is where we
have the three time frames in sync
giving us all three time frames together
giving us a thirty percent if we're
buying or selling at a daily or weekly
area of Interest this is where I would
then add also a 10 to my grade and this
just goes on my strategy and my
confidence just go on for a series of
like 10 different ones where I end up
giving a grade to the trade where then I
can basically identify whether it's
going to be a b setup C setup a setup
and I usually don't take any trades
under AC by the way I graduated high
school with a
2.57 GPA which is a seat in America that
is fine I take a seat of my mom and
she's happy she's you know phenomenal so
I'm gonna take trades that are C plus
anything on there makes no sense so I'm
just applying the same thing so as you
guys can tell here after we identify
that we have our area of Interest this
is where I would then go down to the
four hour in the four hour I have to
wait for it to touch my area of Interest
once we come to our area of Interest
this is where I can identify wow where
having a rejection from EMA
from EMA rejection from structure I
should put here from four hour structure
we also have a
one second we also have a
four hour rejection Candlestick so on
and so forth so we notice we're building
a series of confluences to take the
trade so then this is where I would wait
for the session to hit whether it's New
York or London session after here this
is where I entered the trade on the one
I entered on the 30 minute time frame on
this bearish engulfing and on this
potential left head right shoulder so
this is where I would come here and I
would just add a 30 minute bearish
engulfing so the confluencing should be
30 minute bearish engulfing
uh seven would be Head and Shoulders
eight would be rejection from 30 minute
EMA like you see how I'm building a
series of conferences and again keep in
mind all of these confluences have a
certain grade towards a trade that is
exactly what I break down and I
explained in my set and forget strategy
so this trade right here after I
identified my entry point which is going
to be after this Parish engulfing I put
my stop loss above the right shoulder
because again we have left head right
shoulder and I'm going to be fully
transparent and completely honest this
was a very tight stop loss I usually
have my stop loss above the head because
again this right here this could have
decided to have created a larger right
shoulder to then keep going to the
downside but since I saw such a strong
30 minute bearish engulfing with taking
the trade at right at eight in the
morning as you guys can tell down here
there's pretty much again setting
yourself up for Success because you know
New York session is about a kick in so
there's a lot of momentum that's going
to hit this trade so this is why I had
my stop loss a little bit tighter on
this trade and this is where I
identified my take profit on a daily
Zone because again
I am a swing slash intraday Trader so if
I am using the higher time frames to
identify the trend why would I place
four hour one hour take profits it's
kind of you're leaving so much money on
the table so this is where I would enter
on the one hour 30 minute four hour
deliver my entries and then my take
profit is based off of the next
structure point so this is where I come
here on the daily time frame and I
notice the next structure Point has this
solid zone right here where we have one
two three four five touches and I just
found the next round psychological level
which is 8 900. I usually like to get
out right before it hits the wrong
psychological level because usually what
happens is that you have this exact
situation here where it tapped it barely
to the T so I ended up closing this
trade not fully at my take profit and
obviously some Brokers aren't gonna hit
it because you know spread and stuff but
my actual trade profit ended up hitting
somewhere around here because I just
more than I needed because I need to
minimum I mean one to two risks to
reward to take a trade I don't really
need anything more anything more would
be great but I'd say it's almost being a
little bit greedy and this trade
probably took anywhere from me like I
think the trade literally took like six
eight hours to play out it was very fast
so I didn't have to set and forget that
long as you guys saw with my simple
strategy I catch these trades all of the
time that's why I think swing trading is
one of the best approaches to take to
the market because it is stress free and
then when you catch the trend you can
have immense profits with little to no
drop down because you're setting
yourself up for Success you're not just
buying on the lower time frames fighting
the markets if you're scalping you're
literally fighting the markets you want
to catch an Impulse up or catch an
Impulse down versus when you're swing
trading into day trading like I do
you're just going with the flow of the
market let's say the current of the
ocean is going north you're gonna just
ride the wave North on the long run
versus catching those little ripples
back how the scalpers do nothing against
you guys but I just personally think
swing trading is a lot more effective
and the profits are much larger and
Truth really thanks to swing trading and
the way that I trade I've been able to
create massive amounts of wealth and you
the person watching this video right now
I'm sure you're starting with zero or
something just like I did I literally
started with nothing I was at Dunkin
Donuts five years ago no knowledge no
experience no contact no degree little
to no money until one day one day I got
there once I mastered the skill set and
then I got to the point where money
stopped being the main thing that's why
I started doing these things just giving
back to you guys and dropping all of
this wisdom that I've learned over the
course of five years learning this
endless and I'd say beautiful craft
because you learned so much about
yourself and I started doing these
videos just because people were
demanding on how did I get these sniper
entries and how did I learn how to
analyze the markets so simple and I used
to just do it on my Instagram stories
all the time but there's so much time
you can just put into an Instagram story
so I just started putting these videos
together for you guys you guys love it
and now I'm hoping people reach the same
exact results that I have so they can
live the life of the dreams and
literally do whatever they want so don't
ever have to go back to a job ever again
so if you want to know more about my set
and forget strategy and you want to see
if you can make anywhere from a thousand
to a thousand five hundred dollars a
week as a beginner Trader using my
certificate strategy in under three
months just hit the link in the
description below where there's a video
there where it's going to teach you more
about my strategy and if you want I can
literally be your Mentor I teach my
students every single week I enter one
weekly Zoom call with them we chat it up
in the Discord where I'm literally
dropping wisdom back and forth learning
from them and then you guys learning
from me where I give you guys my top
three top four pairs for the week where
I teach the traders to become profitable
in under three months and they follow my
strategy to the team so I appreciate you
guys watching this video all the way to
the end if you guys want to see more
videos like this make sure you guys hit
that like And subscribe button and I'll
see you guys in the next video